Register of the World War I subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Booklet, "Fahrplanbuch für den Dienstgebrauch, Heft 2, Schnell- und Personenzüge,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 29: 15)
  Militär Eisenbahndirektion 11, Dorpat. Gültig vom 1. August ab bis auf weiteres.
- Booklet, "Die Heimatpost,", 1916 January 1 (Box-folder 29: 16)
- Booklet, "Kriegs-Ausstellung 1914/1915 der Autographen-Sammlung Darmstaedter," (Box-folder 29: 17)
- Booklet, "Das Kriegsarchiv der Universitätsbibliothek zu Jena, 1914-1916,", 1917 (Box-folder 29: 18)
- Calendar, "Roter Kreuz-Kalender für das Jahr 1916," (Box-folder 29: 19)
- Calendar, Wochenlektion, 1915 (Box-folder 29: 20)
  Daily tear-away calendar, beginning 2 November, with Bible verses and reflections.
- Correspondence, envelope with wax seals, 1918 (Box-folder 29: 21)
  Only an envelope, no letter.
- Correspondence, Frau Rektor Voight and Fräulein Meta Wöhlbier, circa 1917, 1919 (Box-folder 29: 22)
  Includes letters, field postcards, envelopes, and other associated materials. The letters discuss sending food to the German military and procedures for doing so.
- Drawing, Alfred von Tirpitz, undated (Box-folder 29: 23)
  Print of a drawn portrait of Grand Admiral von Tirpitz, Secretary of State of the German Imperial Naval Office from 1897 to 1916.
- Drawing, August von Mackensen, undated (Box-folder 29: 24)
  Print of a drawn portrait of August von Mackensen, German military officer who served as, among other things, field marshal during World War I.
- Drawing, Kronprinz Wilhelm von Preussen, undated (Box-folder 29: 25)
  Print of a drawn portrait of Crown Prince Wilhelm, son of Kaiser Wilhelm II and commander of the 5th Army and then the Army Group German Crown Prince during World War I.
- Drawing, "Der Sturm bricht los,", undated (Box-folder 29: 26)
  "Nach einer Zeichnung von M. Barascudts." Print of a drawing of a man working in a field, looking back towards a stormy sky that includes a woman wielding a sword appearing in the clouds.
- Flyer, "Bekanntmachung betreffend Erzeugung des Kriegsmaterials durch Eisen- und Stahlwerke,", 1917 November 10 (Box-folder 29: 27)
- Flyer, "Deutsche Einquartierung 1914," (Box-folder 29: 28)
- Flyer, "Deutsche Männer, Deutsche Frauen. Der Weltkrieg drängt zur Entscheidung,", 1917 February 1 (Box-folder 29: 29)
- Flyers, Durch Luftballon, 1918 (Box-folder 29: 30)
  German military propaganda. Includes A.P. 7 "Deutsche Soldaten!;" A.P. 61, "Amerikanische Soldaten in Frankreich;" A.P. 67 "Die italienische Beute am Piave;" and A.P. 94 "Deutsche Stimmen über die Niederlage."
- Flyers, German occupation of Lithuania, 1917 (Box-folder 29: 31)
  Notices from the head of the Germany military administration in Lithuania, largely about crimes that have been committed and rewards being offered for information. In German, Slovenian, Yiddish, Lithuanian, Polish
- Flyer, "Landtags-Ersatzwahl 1917,", 1917 November 6 (Box-folder 29: 32)
- Flyer, "Landwirtschaftliche Betriebsunternehmer, beachtet die Unfallverhütungsvorschriften!,", undated (Box-folder 29: 33)
- Flyer, "Liebe Krieger!,", 1915 May 20 (Box-folder 29: 34)
  Flyer addressed to German prisoners of war in France. There is also an envelope addressed to a German prisoner of war in France, Fritz Weber, but it is not related to the flyer.
- Flyer, "Mieteausfall-Statistik,", 1914 October (Box-folder 29: 35)
- Flyer, "Polizeiverordnung,", 1915 September 14 (Box-folder 29: 36)
  From the German Head of Civil Administration in Suwalki, Poland. In German and Polish.
- Flyer, "Republik bedeutet Frieden und Freiheit!,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 29: 37)
  German propaganda urging French soldiers to join the German cause.
- Flyer, "Verordnung betreffend Verlängerung der Wechsel-u,", 1915 July 28 (Box-folder 29: 38)
  In German and Polish.
- Flyer, "VI. Soldatenunterhaltung im Kaisergarten,", circa 1915 July (Box-folder 29: 39)
- Flyer, "Viehzählung am 1. Dezember 1917,", 1917 November 20 (Box-folder 29: 40)
- Flyer, "Zum Tode verurteilt! Ein französischer Aufruf an das deutsche Volk,", 1917 (Box-folder 29: 41)
  German translation of a 17 May 1917 editorial from a French newspaper, Le Matin.
- Flyer, "Zusatzbrotkarten,", 1916 August 30 (Box-folder 29: 42)
- Flyers and leaflets, German anti-war propaganda, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 29: 43)
  Includes "Kriegsblätter für das deutsche Volk," No. 14, April 1916; "Die Feldpost," Nos. 8 and 10, January and February 1916; flyers; and "Briefe aus Deutschland," circa July 1916.
- Image, "Unser geliebter Kaiser,", circa 1914 (Box-folder 29: 44)
  Nach einer Aufnahme v. Hofphotographen W. Niederastroth. Kunstverlagsanstalt Gerhard Stalling, Oldenburg i. Gr. Includes a quote from Kaiser Wilhelm II to the German people, 6 August 1914: "Noch nie ward Deutschland überwunden, wenn es einig war."
- Leaflet, "Aluminium Kupfer Messing Nickel Zinn ist genug im Lande! Gebt es heraus, das Heer braucht es!,", 1917 (Box-folder 29: 45)
- Leaflet, "An die ländlichen Hausfrauen!,", undated (Box-folder 29: 46)
- Leaflet, "An die Soldaten!,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 29: 47)
- Leaflets, "Ans der Heimat und dem Felde,", 1915 (Box-folder 29: 48)
  Berichte der Westermänner von drinnen und draussen im Kriegsjahre 1914/15. Includes Nos. 1-4 (February, March, July, and October).
- Leaflet, "Anweisung für den Gebrauch der Stimmzettel,", undated (Box-folder 29: 49)
- Leaflet, "Arbeiter! Handwerker! Bürger! Genossen! Männer! Frauen!,", circa 1919 (Box-folder 29: 50)
- Leaflet, "Auszug aus der Verordnung betreffend Erhebung einer Stempelabgabe beim Umsatz von Wertpapieren,", 1917 August 27 (Box-folder 29: 51)
  In German, Lithuanian, Polish, Slovenian, and Yiddish.
- Leaflets, "Beglaubigte Abschrift,", 1916-1917 (Box-folder 29: 52)
  Stellvertretendes Generalkommando I. Armeekorps, Sekt. IIIb, Königsberg. These three leaflets appear to be reports from the field and are dated 4 and 9 November 1916; 25 April and 1 May 1917; and 27 April and 2 May 1917.
- Leaflet, "Brot, Friede und Freiheit!,", undated (Box-folder 29: 53)
- Leaflet, "Deutsch-polnische Kämpfe?,", undated (Box-folder 29: 54)
- Leaflet, "Deutscher Luftflotten-Verein,", 1915 May 1 (Box-folder 29: 55)
  Provides information about the Deutscher Luftflotten-Verein, as well as a donation form.
- Leaflet, "Deutschlands Brotversorgung,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 29: 56)
- Leaflet, "Dörrt Gemüse und Obst!,", 1915 (Box-folder 29: 57)
  Includes instructions for how to dry various fruits and vegetables.
- Leaflet, "Einführung in die höhere Mathematik, für Studierende und zum Selbststudium von Dr. Hans von Mangoldt,", circa 1914 (Box-folder 29: 58)
  Informational leaflet about the publication, including reviews and an order form.
- Leaflet, "Einweihung des zur Ehre und dem Gedächtnis der für ihr Vaterland gefallenen Helden errichteten Denkmals auf dem Friedhof Poltorowschisna,", 1916 December 3 (Box-folder 29: 59)
- Leaflet, "Euer Hochwohlgeboren!,", 1915 October (Box-folder 29: 60)
  Der Protektor der Königlichen Albertus-Universität.
- Leaflets, Festschriften, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 29: 61)
  Includes leaflets for the celebration of the 500th anniversary of the "Herrschaft des Hohenzollernhauses in dem Brandenburgisch Preussischen Staate" on 24 October 1915, as well as for services "am Geburtstage Sr. Majestät des Kaisers und Königs" on 27 January 1916.
- Leaflet, "Fünfprozentige Deutsche Reichsanleihe von 1915,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 29: 62)
  Two leaflets, one for the Zweite Kriegsanleihe, and one for the Dritte Kriegsanleihe.
- Leaflet, "Gemeinverständliche Belehrung über die Ruhr,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 29: 63)
- Leaflet, "Gott mit uns! Die türkische Frage? Frieden?,", 1914 August 7 (Box-folder 29: 64)
- Leaflet, "Gottesgericht über die Anstifter des Weltkriegs,", 1915 April (Box-folder 30: 1)
  Published by the Deutscher Postverband.
- Leaflet, "Die grosse Zeit,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 30: 2)
  Informational leaflet about the publication, an illustrated military history, including a subscription card to return.
- Leaflet, "Haben Polen und Litauer Anrechte auf Ostpreussen?,", undated (Box-folder 30: 3)
- Leaflet, "In Feindes Land. Ruhmgekrönt ist das deutsche Heer,", undated (Box-folder 30: 4)
- Leaflet, "Kriegsanleiheversicherung,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 30: 5)
- Leaflet, "Leibniz-Feldpost,", 1915 May 1 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  Selected pages from Issue No. 10, consisting of a list of names, "Unsere Mitarbeiter im Heeresdienst," that also indicates recipients of the Iron Cross medal. Also included is a photographic supplement to the issue.
- Leaflet, "Ludendorff-Spende für Kriegsbeschädigte! Sammel-Liste,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 30: 7)
- Leaflet, "Meinen lieben Brüdern aus Harsleben einen herzlichen Gruss!,", undated (Box-folder 30: 8)
- Leaflet, "Merkblatt zur sechsten Kriegsanleihe,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 30: 9)
- Leaflet, "Mitteilung,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 30: 10)
  Statement of opposition to the war supported by a variety of German professors, including Albert Einstein.
- Leaflet, "Nicht in die vordere Linie mitzunehmen! Liebe Freunde!,", 1916 July (Box-folder 30: 11)
  Patriotic German propaganda appealing to citizens to join the Germany Army.
- Leaflet, "Pourquoi continuer la lutte?,", 1918 October (Box-folder 30: 12)
  German propaganda on the French front.
- Leaflets, published by Otto Elsner, Berlin, 1918 (Box-folder 30: 13)
  German propaganda leaflets: No. 29, "Amerikanische Arbeiter für die Vernichtung Deutschlands;" No. 31, "Frieden nur mit einem besiegten Deutschland!;" No. 32, "Amerika lehnt jedes Friedensangebot ab;" No. 33, "Ein Ausbruch wilden Deutschenhasses;" No. 34, "Wie der Vielverband für das Recht der unterdrückten Völker kämpft!;" No. 35, "Hetze über Hetze gegen alles Deutsche;" No. 37, "Amerika will Deutschland boykottieren."
- Leaflet, "Rettung. So oder so?,", circa 1914 (Box-folder 30: 14)
  Issue No. 15, "Herausgegeben von dem Zentralvorstand des Deutschen Hauptvereins des Blauen Kreuzes mit dem Sitz in Barmen."
- Leaflet, "Schafft eine zweite Gemüseernte, helft alle mit, die Ihr dazu in der Lage seid!,", undated (Box-folder 30: 15)
- Leaflet, "Sehr geehrter Herr!,", undated (Box-folder 30: 16)
  Letter from Der Ausschuss für Verständigung über Kriegsziele soliciting donations.
- Leaflet, "Soldaten! Webt, wenn möglich, auch im Felde neue Mitglieder!,", undated (Box-folder 30: 17)
- Leaflet, "Thorner Kriegswohlfahrtspflege,", undated (Box-folder 30: 18)
- Leaflet, "Unsere Kriegsziele,", 1915 (Box-folder 30: 19)
- Leaflet, "Urschriftlich der Stadtverordneten-Versammlung,", 1914 August 13 (Box-folder 30: 20)
- Leaflets, "Volksbund zum Schutze der deutschen Kriegs- und Zivilgefangenen,", 1919, undated (Box-folder 30: 21)
- Leaflet, "Das Wahlrecht,", undated (Box-folder 30: 22)
- Leaflet, "Wider den Erzfeind!,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 30: 23)
  Subtitle: "Achtung! Soldaten! Der Feind hat vergiftende Waffen! Notwendigste Aufklärung und Warnung zur Rettung und Vorsicht an die deutschen Krieger in Heer und Marine! Erst lesen und dann sofort weitergeben!"
- Leaflet, "Zum ehrenden Gedächtnis unseren gefallenen Helden,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 30: 24)
  Includes names of German soldiers killed in battle through 30 June 1915, along with the place and date of death.
- Leaflet, "Zur belgischen Frage,", 1915 (Box-folder 30: 25)
- Leaflet, "Zur Vereidigung des Landsturm-Infanterie-Bataillons Grossenhain,", 1914 August 27 (Box-folder 30: 26)
- Music, "Bundeslied/S'iuzna piesen',", undated (Box-folder 30: 27)
  Includes introductory text and the music and lyrics of a national song. In German and Bulgarian.
- Newspaper clipping, Kölnische Zeitung: Literatur und Unterhaltungsblatt, 1917 April 22 (Box-folder 30: 28)
- Poster, "An das deutsche Volk!,", 1917 January 12 (Box-folder 30: 29)
  Artwork by Franz Stassen. Patriotic German propaganda.
- Poster, "Denk an die Ludendorff-Spende für Kriegsbeschädigte!,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 30: 30)
- Poster, "Und Eure Pflicht? Zeichnet Kriegsanleihe,", 1918 (Box-folder 30: 31)
  Artwork by Horrmeyer.
- Poster, "Gegen England!,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 30: 32)
  Artwork by Hans Rudolph Schulze.
- Poster, "Kriegs Anleihe: Hilft den Hütern Eures Glückes,", 1918 (Box-folder 30: 33)
  Artwork by W. Georgi.
- Poster, "Die Ludendorff-Spende ist der Dank-Altar des deutschen Volkes!,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 30: 34)
- Poster, "Wir lassen uns nicht aushungern!,", 1915 (Box-folder 30: 35)
  Artwork by Friedrich Kaskeline.
- Press release, "Pressespiegel über Stimmung der Kiewer Presse in der Woche vom 6.-12. October,", 1918 October 15 (Box-folder 30: 36)
  Discusses recent press about events in Russia and the German military's presence there.
- Printed matter, Auskunftstelle für Vermisste, circa 1917 (Box-folder 30: 37)
  Auf Anregung des Päpstlichen Stuhles errichtet von Bischof Dr. Schulte, Paderborn, Bischöfliches Generalvikariat. Includes a booklet, Liste 263 published 26 July 1917, and a leaflet, Liste 279, with the names of missing soldiers from the French Army. In German and French.
- Printed matter, German occupation of Poland, 1916-1917, undated (Box-folder 30: 38)
  Includes ration cards, blank forms, and a flyer.
- Printed matter, Gold gab ich zur Wehr - Eisen nahm ich zur Her, circa 1917-1918 (Box-folder 30: 39)
  Includes blank postcards, business card-sized calendars for 1917 and 1918, a flyer, a leaflet, and a small poster.
- Printed matter, Gold- und Silberankaufshilfsstelle, 1916, undated (Box-folder 30: 40)
  Includes tags, bags, blank forms, and certificates.
- Printed matter, lyrics, 1914, 1917-1919 (Box-folder 30: 41)
  Includes postcards, flyers and leaflets, some of which include the music, while others note which melody should be used.
- Printed matter, miscellaneous, 1914, 1918-1919, undated (Box-folder 30: 42)
  Includes postcards, ration cards, bookmarks, tags, stationery, a death announcement, leaflets, and blank forms.
- Printed matter, Rote Kreuz [German Red Cross], 1914-1918 (Box-folder 30: 43)
  Includes blank postcards, an envelope with stamps, leaflets, correspondence (mostly form letters), posters, and other printed matter.
- Program, "Kriegsbrotabend, veranstaltet von den Kirchlichen Jugendvereinen, Jünglingsverein und Jungfrauenverein zu Moringen,", 1915 March (Box-folder 30: 44)
- Ration cards, Stadtkreis Königsberg, circa 1917-1919 (Box-folder 30: 45)
- Booklet, "Auf auf mein Herz mit Freuden, Ein Ostergruss für das Deutsche Heer,", circa 1916 (Box-folder 30: 46)
- Booklet, "Die Bildung der Sozialdemokratischen Arbeitsgemeinschaft,", undated (Box-folder 30: 47)
- Booklet, "The Church and International Peace - The Cause of the War,", undated (Box-folder 30: 48)
- Booklet, "The Conditions of the Belgian Workmen Now Refugees in England,", 1917 (Box-folder 30: 49)
- Booklet, "Deutsche Kriegswochenschau,", 1917 September 16 (Box-folder 30: 50)
- Booklet, "Deutschland als Staat im Vergleich zu anderen Ländern,", 1917 (Box-folder 30: 51)
- Booklet, "Englands Wirtschaftskrieg und unsere U. Boote,", 1917 (Box-folder 30: 52)
- Booklet, "Éphémérides des Campagnes Belges en Afrique (1914-1917),", 1918 (Box-folder 30: 53)
- Booklet, "Feudalism the Fire: Help Burn it Up. Support Wilson and His War Aims,", 1918 March 28 (Box-folder 31: 1)
- Booklet, "Flowers From the Field of Franco-American Friendship,", circa 1920 (Box-folder 31: 2)
- Booklet, The Bystander's "Fragments from France,", undated (Box-folder 31: 3)
- Booklet, "Fröhlich in Hoffnung,", undated (Box-folder 31: 4)
- Booklet, "The German White Book with Important Official Addenda. Documents Anent the Outbreak of the European War issued by the German Government, Authorized Edition for America,", circa 1914 (Box-folder 31: 5)
- Booklet, "Gott mit uns! Kriegsgebetbüchlein für die deutsche Armee,", 1916 (Box-folder 31: 6)
- Booklet, "'I was there!' with the Yanks in France,", 1919 (Box-folder 31: 7)
- Booklet, "The Indian,", circa 1918 (Box-folder 31: 8)
- Booklet, "Die Kriegsziele unserer Feinde,", 1917 (Box-folder 31: 9)
- Booklet, "Die neue Kriegsküche,", undated (Box-folder 31: 10)
- Booklet, "Odezwy I Rozporzadzenia z Czasow Okupacyi Rosyjskiej Lwowa 1914-1915,", 1916 (Box-folder 31: 11)
- Booklet, The Kolynos "Parley Voo Booklet,", undated (Box-folder 31: 12)
  With photocopy of related article.
- Booklet, "Le 'Poilu' a Gagné la Guerre,", undated (Box-folder 31: 13)
- Booklet, "The President's War Message,", 1917 (Box-folder 31: 14)
- Booklet, "Rahnsdorfer Kriegsfürsorge,", 1916 (Box-folder 31: 15)
- Booklet, "A Reply to 'Scaremongerings' and an Open Letter to Lord Northcliffe,", circa 1915 (Box-folder 31: 16)
- Booklet, "Report on the Use of Tri-Lens Aerial Mapping Cameras in the American Expeditionary Forces in France,", 1919 (Box-folder 31: 17)
- Booklet, "The Sapper,", 1919 January (Box-folder 31: 18)
- Booklet, "Der Sinn des Lebens,", 1917 (Box-folder 31: 19)
- Booklet, "Sturm und Stille. Predigt über Matthai 8, 23-27,", 1915 February (Box-folder 31: 20)
- Booklet, "Tragbare Feldbücherein,", undated (Box-folder 31: 21)
- Booklet, "The Truth About Germany and the War in Europe,", 1914 (Box-folder 31: 22)
- Booklet, "United States Food Administration Bulletin No. 6. Creation of United States Food Administration Plans for Wheat, Flour, and Bread Control; Personnel Announcements; Food, an International Problem,", 1917 (Box-folder 31: 23)
- Booklet, "Wach auf mein Herz, die Nacht ist hin!,", undated (Box-folder 31: 24)
- Booklet, "Die Wohnungsfrage vor und nach dem Kriege,", 1916 (Box-folder 31: 25)
- Drawing, "Les Atrocités Allemandes,", 1915 April (Box-folder 31: 26)
- Drawings, British cartoons, circa 1914-1915 (Box-folder 31: 27)
- Drawing, Cylindrical percussion hand grenade - 1917 type, undated (Box-folder 31: 28)
- Drawing, San Francisco Chronicle, "Shall Hun or Home Survive?,", 1918 September 29 (Box-folder 31: 29)
- Flyer, "An unsere feldgrauen Brüder und Beschützer!,", 1915 January 27 (Box-folder 31: 30)
- Flyer, "Aufruf. Landeseinwohner!,", undated (Box-folder 31: 31)
- Flyer, "Befehl des die Stadt besetzt habenden russischen Kommandos,", 1914 August 28 (Box-folder 31: 32)
- Flyer, "Bekanntmachung … Es liegt offenbar Brandstiftung vor,", 1917 November 11 (Box-folder 31: 33)
  Notice from the head of the Lithuanian Military Administration about a fire (arson) that burned down a barn and the crops inside and asking for more information, with a reward offered.
- Flyer, "Bekanntmachung … Während des Aufenthalts der Motorradfahrer…,", 1915 November 6 (Box-folder 31: 34)
  Notice from the chief of the German government for Lithuania about keeping dogs leashed to prevent accidents with motorcycles.
- Flyer, "Der Dank des Heeres an die Heimat,", 1917 April 24 (Box-folder 31: 35)
- Flyer, "Deutsche Männer,deutsche Frauen … Wir brauchen euer Opfer!,", 1917 February 1 (Box-folder 31: 36)
- Flyer, "Der deutschen Kaisern,", undated (Box-folder 31: 37)
- Flyer, "Deutscher Weltkrieg,", undated (Box-folder 31: 38)
- Flyer, "Deutschlands Frauen zu einer Kaiseringeburtstagsspende,", undated (Box-folder 31: 39)
- Flyer, "Deutschland steht gegen eine Welt von Feinden, …,", undated (Box-folder 31: 40)
- Flyer, "Fuchs im Bau,", undated (Box-folder 31: 41)
- Flyer, "Kauft keine amerikanischen Nähmaschinen!,", undated (Box-folder 31: 42)
- Flyer, "Landwirte! Unser heer braucht noch dringend Hafer oder Mengkorn,", 1917 May (Box-folder 31: 43)
- Flyer, "Notquartier…,", undated (Box-folder 31: 44)
- Flyer, "Soldatenunterhaltung im Kaisergarten…,", 1915 August 1 (Box-folder 31: 45)
- Flyer, "Soldaţilor Români! …,", undated (Box-folder 31: 46)
- Flyer, "Sonn' auf!,", undated (Box-folder 31: 47)
- Flyer, "…Verkaufsverpflichtung von rohen Kanin-, hasen- und Katzenfellen,", 1917 November 24 (Box-folder 31: 48)
- Flyer, "Vertrauliche nur für die Redaktionen bestimmte Notiz,", 1916 November 28 (Box-folder 31: 49)
- Flyer, "Wilde Lohnforderungen u. wilde Streiks!,", undated (Box-folder 31: 50)
- Flyer, addressed to British soldiers about women working on the home front, circa 1918 (Box-folder 31: 51)
- Flyers, published by Hartungsche Buchdruckerei, 1916-1918 (Box-folder 31: 52)
- Flyers, published by Nessel-Anbau-Gesellschaft, undated (Box-folder 32: 1)
- Flyers, re German occupation of Poland, 1916, undated (Box-folder 32: 2)
- Form, Amtliche Fürsorgestelle für Kriegshinterbliebene, undated (Box-folder 32: 3)
- Form, Bestellt die "Kriegszeitung der Festung Borkum,", undated (Box-folder 32: 4)
- Leaflet, "A.H.V. der A.T.V. Ostmark,", 1915 November 1 (Box-folder 32: 5)
- Leaflet, "Anweisung für den Gebrauch der Stimmzettel,", undated (Box-folder 32: 6)
- Leaflet, "Arbeiter! Proletarier! Das war der erste Streich der 'demokratischen' Regierung,", undated (Box-folder 32: 7)
- Leaflet, "Auf zur 9ten Kriegsanleihe,", 1918 (Box-folder 32: 8)
- Leaflet, "Die Augen auf!,", undated (Box-folder 32: 9)
- Leaflet, "A Brief Memorandum Relating to the War between Gt. Britain and Germany,", 1914 October 8 (Box-folder 32: 10)
- Leaflet, "Deutschlands Feld-heer und Heim-heer,", undated (Box-folder 32: 11)
- Leaflet, "Deutschlands Schicksal in einem zukünftigen Kriege wenn Belgien die Basis englischer Luftangriffe ist!,", undated (Box-folder 32: 12)
- Leaflet, "Eiserne Blätter,", undated (Box-folder 32: 13)
- Leaflet, "…gebt Kupfer, Messing, Rotguss, Tombak, Bronze,", circa 1917 (Box-folder 32: 14)
- Leaflet, "In französischer Gefangenschaft,", undated (Box-folder 32: 15)
- Leaflet, "James F.J. Archibald Uncensored War Talk,", 1915 (Box-folder 32: 16)
- Leaflet, "Jugenddank für Kriegsbeschädigte," Charlottenburg, 1916 (Box-folder 32: 17)
- Leaflet, "Kameraden, Genossen und Frauen! Der Militarismus ist für immer beseitigt,", undated (Box-folder 32: 18)
- Leaflet, "Mahnruf,", undated (Box-folder 32: 19)
- Leaflet, "Merkblatt für den Scheck und Überweisungsverkehr,", circa 1916 (Box-folder 32: 20)
- Leaflet, "Pour mieux se connaître,", 1918-1919 (Box-folder 32: 21)
- Leaflet, "Reichsgetreideordung für die Ernte 1917,", 1917 June 21 (Box-folder 32: 22)
- Leaflet, "Those 'Gentleman' of Germany,", undated (Box-folder 32: 23)
- Letter, from R. Brack to Thelma Keefe, 1917 September 12 (Box-folder 32: 24)
- Letters, re war libraries, 1917 (Box-folder 32: 25)
- Map, Eisenbahnkarte von Österreich, Ungarn und den Balkanländern, April 1905 (Box-folder 32: 26)
- Map, Skizze der Sammelstelle I/78, undated (Box-folder 32: 27)
- Map, La Victoire des Allies [map of the Western Front], undated (Box-folder 32: 28)
- Map images, Gravelotte, 7 Jul 1905 (Box-folder 32: 29)
  Prints of digital photos taken of an oversized map of Gravelotte published in 1882 (for the map itself, see Map case, Folder 6). An attempt was made to order the photos from left to right, top to bottom.
- Map index, Namenverzeichnis zu den Karten zum Kriege gegen Russland, undated (Box-folder 32: 30)
  Index only; the map that is supposed to accompany it is missing.
- Music, "Bitte des Feldheeres an die Heimat" [German song], undated (Box-folder 32: 31)
- Music, "Der Kinder Kriegsgebet" [German song], undated (Box-folder 32: 32)
- Music, "Patriotic Songs" [American], undated (Box-folder 32: 33)
- Newspaper, Belgischer Kurier, 1918 November 12-14 (Box-folder 32: 34)
- Newspaper, La Presse, 1914 October 19 (Box-folder 32: 35)
- Newspaper clipping, "The Land of Mazeppa,", 1916 (Box-folder 32: 36)
- Newspaper clipping, New York Times Magazine, "New York Soldiers Joke With Pencil and Pen,", 1919 January 12 (Box-folder 32: 37)
- Newspaper clipping, Königsberger Tageblatt Volksblatt für Ostpreussen, "Ostpreussische Flüchtlinge,", 1914 September 17 (Box-folder 32: 38)
- Newspaper clipping, Niederrheinisches Tageblatt, "Verordnungen des Militärkommandanten,", 1918 December 13 (Box-folder 32: 39)
- Newspaper clippings re German food shortage, 1918, undated (Box-folder 32: 40)
- Photograph (aerial), North Flirey, 1918 August 25 (Box-folder 32: 41)
- Photograph, Wilhelm, Crown Prince of Prussia, 1916 (Box-folder 32: 42)